Hey English learners, welcome to this A1
English listening practice video. Today,
let's talk about some different reasons
why people learn English. There are many
reasons to learn English. You probably
have one or two or maybe more reasons
why you're learning English. I want to
talk about different reasons to learn
English today because this is important.
It's important to have a good reason to
learn because when you have a good
reason, it helps keep you focused on
your learning. It helps you continue to
learn and not give up. And it motivates
you. It gives you the motivation you
need to learn English. So, that's what
we're going to talk about today. And
before we do that, I want to remind you
that if you need my help to understand
native English speakers when they speak
fast, then make sure to join my
membership so you can watch my listening
practice seminars in which I help you
understand fast English. So that link is
down below. All right, let's talk about
some different reasons why people learn
English. The first one I want to talk
about is entertainment.
Many people want to learn English
because they like English language
entertainment. Maybe they like watching
TV, TV shows or TV series in English.
Maybe they like watching American
movies, for example. Or perhaps they
really like music and they want to
listen to music in English. Or maybe
they're interested in video games and
they want to talk to other people while
they're playing video games and they
need to talk in English. So
entertainment can be a really good
motivator for people to learn English
and it can also be really effective as
well because when you enjoy something
you do it more, right? When you like
doing something, it's not that hard for
you to do it. You enjoy it. So, you do
it easily.
And when you enjoy doing something, you
focus more on it when you do it, right?
And also you learn more when you enjoy
something, when it's entertaining to
you. You focus more and learn more. You
probably remember more from what you
watch or hear. So, uh I know people who
have accidentally
learned a language, maybe not fluently,
but they've learned uh some language to
uh a good level maybe because they're so
interested in the entertainment
from some country like for example
uh they might really like Korean dramas
and so they watch so many Korean dramas
and eventually they start to understand
Korean.
I've heard of this before. Or maybe
they're really interested in Japanese
anime and they watch so much anime that
eventually they start to understand
Japanese. Maybe they can't speak it, but
they can already understand a lot. This
is pretty crazy because these people
might not even care about the language
of that drama or that anime, but they're
so interested in that entertainment that
they learn the language. That's pretty
cool. So many people can learn English
because they want to watch things in
English or listen to things in English
or maybe they get good at English
because they like playing video games.
This is common. So, this can be a good
reason to learn English. I'm not saying
that this is the best reason uh to play
video games, but I'm saying that many
people learn English because of this
reason. So, that's one thing. Another
reason why many people want to learn
English is because they like traveling.
Learning English makes traveling easier.
So when you travel to an Englishspeaking
country and you can speak English, this
makes things a lot easier. This makes
things simpler. And even if you're
traveling to a country where the people
don't speak English as a native
language, many people probably speak
English as a second language. So, you
can also use English a lot when you
travel to countries that aren't the US
or the UK. Um, if you travel to other
European countries perhaps, uh, you'll
probably be able to speak English with
many people there. So that can really
help you when you travel. It can uh help
you communicate with local people. Uh
maybe uh read signs or websites or
whatever you need when you're traveling
or you're planning a trip. So, that can
help. And you can also uh make friends
when you're traveling. Uh, I've known
people that have made friends when they
travel to other countries because maybe
they take a tour and in that tour group
they speak English to the other tourists
who are taking that tour. So that can
help them make friends with other
tourists or they can make friends with
locals as well. So
learning English can make traveling
easier and funner, right? That's another
good reason to learn English. Another
reason why people might learn English is
because of their career. This is a very
common reason. Maybe you're learning
English to help you in your career. So
if you can speak English, maybe you can
work with international
clients or customers. Uh maybe you can
work in an international company and you
need English because your co-workers
speak English. Um, or maybe if you speak
English, you'll have more opportunities
in your work. Or maybe you'll have the
opportunity to work abroad, work in
another country. So there are many
opportunities
that you uh can have if you speak
English and uh also for
academics for school, right? University.
Um, knowing English can be very helpful
because
it can help you research things in
English. Uh, the internet is full of
information in English. So, if you can
speak English, you have a lot of
information that you can use. uh when
you are doing um different types of
school work uh when you're writing
things for your university
etc. right? You have a lot of
information uh that you can use when you
speak English. If this is your reason
for learning English, you want to have
more career opportunities or it helps
you in your uh academics, your school.
Um, this is great, but you should still
have a reason that's more personal. Uh,
you don't want to only learn English
because you have to because uh, your
boss makes you learn English or your
school makes you learn English. It's
also good to have a personal reason uh
why you want to learn not because you
have to learn but because you want to
learn. If you have a more personal
reason it will help you be more
motivated.
So, one more reason why some people
learn English is because of love.
Because they fall in love with someone
who speaks English. Uh if you meet
someone who speaks English and they
don't speak your language, this is the
greatest motivation to learn English
because uh you love this person and you
need to communicate with them and you
can only do this in English. This is a
great motivator.
This is probably the top reason uh the
reason that gives you the most
motivation.
So, uh I know this from experience. I
learned Spanish because of love. because
I fell in love with someone who speaks
that language. So, uh this was uh the
best uh motivator. This gave me the most
motivation to learn. So, most of you
won't do this, but
it's a good lesson for you to know this.
Even if you don't do this, it's good to
know this because it shows you how
important it is to have a good personal
reason to learn a language. When you
have this, it makes learning English
much easier. You want to do it. You
spend more time doing it. Uh it becomes
easier to uh do the necessary things to
learn English. So, even if you don't
fall in love with someone who speaks
English, you should still find a good
personal reason to learn. Okay, I hope
this video was helpful for you and for
your listening. Remember that if you
need my help to understand native
speakers when they speak fast, join my
membership and you'll get my listening
training. Thank you all for watching
this video and I'll talk to you in the
next